<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruth Raichur</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ruth Raichur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How a Selfish DNA Element Hitchikes onto Chromosomes</title>
      <link>/post/2022/01/29/how-a-selfish-dna-hitchikes-onto-chromosomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/01/29/how-a-selfish-dna-hitchikes-onto-chromosomes/</guid>
      <description>  coming soon  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversing the effects of hypermethylation on BRCA1 by CRISPR/Cas9 technology.</title>
      <link>/project/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project6/</guid>
      <description>Breast cancer susceptibility gene 1 (BRCA1) is a tumor suppressor gene involved in the pathogenesis of tumors specific to breast and ovarian cancer. The normal biological functions of this gene are primarily associated with controlling cell proliferation by DNA damage repair and cell cycle checkpoint control that include promoting apoptosis and controlling hypermethylation (Krasteva et al., 2012). Mechanisms that cause loss of function in BRCA1 include somatic mutations, DNA hypermethylation, dysregulation of transcriptional activators, and BRCA1 locus binding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-Seq Final Project</title>
      <link>/project/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project5/</guid>
      <description>source(&amp;quot;bio321g_rnaseq_utils.R&amp;quot;) This report analyzes the RNA-seq expression patterns of a dataset focused on varying genotypes of Arabidopsis thaliana. We are primarily interested in understanding how the differences in gene expression between the light and dark conditions vary by genotype.
The RNA-seq data consists of sample genotypes with the following description matching each code:
 Col: wild-type Arabidopsis thaliana. (WT).
 14B: a mutant lacking two genes for a plant specific translation initiation factor, eIFiso4G1 (AT5g57870) and eIFiso4G2 (At2g24050).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missense mutations in genes Chd2 and Myocd interacting with Myod1 likely cause abnormal skeletal phenotypes that predispose preterm birth by premature rupture of membranes.</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this study was to postulate an underlying cause of a patient’s phenotype that is likely genetic. Missense mutations were identified in a 13 year old XY individual (Decipher ID: 290490 ) in two genes presenting multiple abnormal skeletal phenotypes such as protruding ears, long face, long philtrum, short nose, low posterior hair line and long fingers as well as preterm birth by premature rupture of membranes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Gli Enhancer Target Gene Osr2 Involved In Embryonic Limb Morphogenesis By Hedgehog Signal Regulation.</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this study was to identify a gene with intersecting Gli binding sites and H3K27ac hallmarks that have associations with human limb abnormalities. The intersection between HH responsive H3K27ac sites and Gli binding region identified 340 active Gli enhancers target genes with about 20+ sites mostly involved with limb, digit, and embryonic morphogenesis. One of these genes was selected for an in-depth analysis to determine the likelihood of Gli enhancers mediated Hedgehog signaling in this gene that regulates limb development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Majors Success Rates</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting Majors Dataset majors &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fivethirtyeight/data/master/college-majors/recent-grads.csv&amp;quot;) level_key &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;Computers &amp;amp; Mathematics&amp;quot; =&amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Engineering&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Industrial Arts &amp;amp; Consumer Services&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Business&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Biology &amp;amp; Life Science&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Agriculture &amp;amp; Natural Resources&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Physical Sciences&amp;quot;= &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Health&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Social Science&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Humanities &amp;amp; Liberal Arts&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Psychology &amp;amp; Social Work&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Education&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Law &amp;amp; Public Policy&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Arts&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Communication&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Communications &amp;amp; Journalism&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Communication&amp;quot;) majors &amp;lt;- majors%&amp;gt;% select(Rank, Major, Total, Men, Women, Major_category, ShareWomen, Employed, Unemployed, Unemployment_rate) %&amp;gt;% mutate(MoreWomen = ifelse(ShareWomen &amp;gt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Movies based on the Bechdel Test and Movie Ratings</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis library(readr) next_bechdel_test &amp;lt;- bechdel_test &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;SDS 348_bechdel_test.csv&amp;quot;) movie_ratings &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;IMDB-Movie-Data.csv&amp;quot;) Introduction The Bechdel test, also known as the Bechdel-Wallace test, is a measure of how women are represented in movies. When it was first created in 1985, there were only 3 critera for a movie to pass the test: 1. the movie must have (at least) two named women in it 2. who talk to each other 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications and Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Publications:
*Equally contributing authors &amp;amp; Co-corresponding authors Liu, S.* &amp;amp;, Friedrich, M.* &amp;amp; ,  Raichur, R. * , Gong, D., Kehl, N., Gong, Q., Schmidt, V., Gustafsson, K., Ma, L., Scadden, D., Zhang, F., Chen, F.&amp;amp; Spatiotemporal dynamics of the thymus reveal changes underlying immune decline and regeneration.  In Preparation  (2023)
Russell, A.J.C.* , Weir, J.A.* , Nadaf, N.M.* , Shabet, M., Kumar, V., Kambhampati, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
