<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruth Raichur</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ruth Raichur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Missense mutations in CHD2 and MYOCD interacting with MYOD1 likely cause abnormal skeletal phenotypes that predispose preterm birth by premature rupture of membranes.</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this study was to postulate an underlying cause of a patient’s phenotype that is likely genetic. Missense mutations were identified in a 13 year old XY individual (Decipher ID: 290490) in two genes presenting multiple abnormal skeletal phenotypes such as protruding ears, long face, long philtrum, short nose, low posterior hair line and long fingers as well as preterm birth by premature rupture of membranes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Gli Enhancer Target Gene Osr2 Involved In Embryonic Limb Morphogenesis By Hedgehog Signal Regulation.</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this study was to identify a gene with intersecting Gli binding sites and H3K27ac hallmarks that have associations with human limb abnormalities. The intersection between HH responsive H3K27ac sites and Gli binding region identified 340 active Gli enhancers target genes with about 20+ sites mostly involved with limb, digit, and embryonic morphogenesis. One of these genes was selected for an in-depth analysis to determine the likelihood of Gli enhancers mediated Hedgehog signaling in this gene that regulates limb development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Python Interact: A Genetics Nerd&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/06/r-and-python-interact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/06/r-and-python-interact/</guid>
      <description>Speaking Two Different Languages Over the course of this semester in Computational Biology, I have come to realize that unlike many languages around the world, coding languages are pretty transferable. Mastering one could potentially make it much easier to pick up another and, better yet, there are packages that allow you to speak both languages at the same time and have them seamlessly interact. Being the genetics nerd I am, I find it easiest to illustrate the interactions between R and Python using the very functions that determine who we are from the essence of our being - gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Majors Success Rates</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting Majors Dataset majors &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fivethirtyeight/data/master/college-majors/recent-grads.csv&amp;quot;) level_key &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;Computers &amp;amp; Mathematics&amp;quot; =&amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Engineering&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Industrial Arts &amp;amp; Consumer Services&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Business&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Biology &amp;amp; Life Science&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Agriculture &amp;amp; Natural Resources&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Physical Sciences&amp;quot;= &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Health&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Natural Sciences&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Social Science&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Humanities &amp;amp; Liberal Arts&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Psychology &amp;amp; Social Work&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Education&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Law &amp;amp; Public Policy&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Arts&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Communication&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Communications &amp;amp; Journalism&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;Communication&amp;quot;) majors &amp;lt;- majors%&amp;gt;% select(Rank, Major, Total, Men, Women, Major_category, ShareWomen, Employed, Unemployed, Unemployment_rate) %&amp;gt;% mutate(MoreWomen = ifelse(ShareWomen &amp;gt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Movies based on the Bechdel Test and Movie Ratings</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis library(readr) next_bechdel_test &amp;lt;- bechdel_test &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;SDS 348_bechdel_test.csv&amp;quot;) movie_ratings &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;IMDB-Movie-Data.csv&amp;quot;) Introduction The Bechdel test, also known as the Bechdel-Wallace test, is a measure of how women are represented in movies. When it was first created in 1985, there were only 3 critera for a movie to pass the test: 1. the movie must have (at least) two named women in it 2. who talk to each other 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>  Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
Check out some of my research projects below:
 UCSC Genome Browser: Identifying direct transcriptional targets of Hedgehog signaling in limb development
 Decipher Patient Case Study
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
